Mohammed Abdulsalam

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

Location: Alexandria, Egypt

BACK END DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled back-end devleoper with over **2 year of experience** in **PHP, MySQL**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Laravel**. I worked on several projects using native **PHP** and **MySQL/MariaDB**, and have experience designing REST APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : PHP, SQL, Javascript, TeX

Frameworks : Laravel

Libraries : PHPUnit, PHP Spread Sheet, ECDSA

Databases : MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite

Concepts : OOP, MVC, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, ERD Design, SRS Design

Dev Tools: Vim, Visual Studio Code, XDebug, Vite, Git, Github, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cron, Docker, Insomnia

EXPERIENCE

Back End Developer Feb 2022 – Present

Freelance

GDSC KSU

- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- · Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

Vice Head of Web Development Committee

Sep 2022 – Apr 2023

Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- Make sure the plan is suitable for members
- Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility, through number of sessions

EDUCATION

University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.25/4

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 – Jul 2024

PROJECTS

Bookopia PHP, Laravel, MVC, SCSS Source Code

- A library management system written in PHP / Laravel. Build with MVC architectural pattern
- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, and SCSS
- Utilized Laravel Components to enhance the modularity of the frontend
- Extended **Blade** funcionality by writing customized **Directives**, that help us write less code

Salem Clinic Website PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git Private

- Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a cronjob to backup data periodically

- Developed various utilities to facilitate **RESTful APIs** developing
- Implemented my own **Router, and JWT** utilities

Clinic Management System / ERP System

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned **ERD** based on this analysis
- Used XDebug to facilitate debugging process, and PHPUnit to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used **Socket.IO** under **Node.js** to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients